<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-13T21:08:22-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ipfs</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/IPFS" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ipfs" /><published>2022-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/ipfs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/IPFS"><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-pain-points-of-nfts">The pain points of NFTs</h3>

<p>The initial craze of NFTs was that they are unique and cannot be copied. While this is true for the fundamental definition of what an NFT is,  <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/nft/">a unique unalterable token that is created and stored on the blockchain,</a>  it doesn’t necessarily hold true when applied to the most common use case of NFTs, art.</p>

<p>A recurring pain point with NFT Art is that the ownership is decoupled from the art. Art is created off-chain (in photoshop, digital sketch, scanned drawing etc.) but being owned on the chain. You basically have to create the art and then let people know what token the art is tied to.</p>

<p>In context of widespread art distribution, NFTs don’t track the original art file itself as you don’t actually distribute files on most blockchains (which is where ipfs comes in 👀). At some point it’s hard to keep track of who  <em>has</em>  the art and who  <em>owns</em>  the token. Really the NFT and the ART or only related arbitrarily, just because someone says it is.</p>

<p>My main argument is that although NFTs provide a more visible way to track ownership of digital art, because art and ownership are decoupled, it is difficult to directly attribute ownership<strong>.</strong></p>

<h3 id="could-ipfs-solve-the-issues-of-nfts">Could IPFS solve the issues of NFTs?</h3>

<p>Right now IPFS, a blockchain solution to file distribution, seems like a starting resolution to the issue of coupling Art to NFTs.  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5Uj6uR3fp-U&amp;ab_channel=SimplyExplained">There’s a great youtube video on how IPFS works</a>, but in short — in IPFS you add a file to the IPFS network, it gets a unique hash address/token and multiple people save a copy of that file or parts of that file. So the file and origin of that file is visible to anyone (unlike if it was stored on your laptop or a server where only the owner could access it). In theory, the file is immutable, so if changes are made to that file and it’s re-uploaded, the network keeps track of that — so there is always a true original. Whenever someone wants to get the file they can refer to the unique hash/token and the unique file associated with that hash will be accessible.</p>

<p>To directly compare, when using NFTs alone, you distribute the token and art separately and you have to tell people which token belongs to which art. IPFS automatically ties the token to the art.</p>

<h3 id="ipfs-makes-ownership-more-than-just-a-construct">IPFS makes ownership more than just a construct</h3>

<p>One important thing to understand about IPFS is that it uses content based addressing instead of location based addressing.</p>

<p>With location based addressing, which is used by traditional storage servers, you access the file based on location. You have to know where the file is located, typically the domain name/IP address of the server, to get access to it. With content based addressing however, you access the file based on what the content is, via the unique hash name, to get access. Essentially. instead of figuring out where the content you want is, all you need to know is what that content is. Though the idea of accessing information based on a long unique sequence of characters seems convoluted, other technologies in crypto infrastructure allow you to resolve the hash key as a domain name (so you people ca just the domain not the hash key) like is currently done with IP addresses for HTTP requests. So file access with IPFS can be considered comparatively simple to Web2 file access.</p>

<p>Since access to the file is not defined on location, that means it can be located anywhere which allows IPFS to operate via distributed nodes (individuals running “microservers”) that consequently decentralizes authority of the file. This means no singular person has authority over its deletion, modifications and access.</p>

<p>Decentralized authority almost seems contradictory to the idea of ownership, after all if a creator uploads an IPFS file to the network and doesn’t have authority over it, how can they be considered the owner? Well ownership isn’t an act, it’s a construct. Ownership means nothing if you can’t prove you created it and can’t prove authenticity. In today’s world people really don’t have authority over the digital art they release anyway. Once they share the image online any one can right-click + save as. At least now there is a way to attribute ownership</p>

<p>I could see something like IPFS becoming a standard protocol like HTTPS. If this occurred as a standard, it would make it easy for people to integrate IPFS content to their websites, articles etc. and create an infrastructure for giving fair and appropriate attribution to content use.</p>

<h3 id="ipfs-still-has-gaps-but-it-will-provide-more-than-the-bare-minimum">IPFS still has gaps but it will provide more than the bare minimum</h3>

<p>IPFS overall helps with coupling the art to the token/hash address, it doesn’t avoid the problem of duplication. Just like with a standard NFT art you can copy an image and reupload it to the network under a new content hash and claim the unique ownership associated with that token.</p>

<p>I’ve sort of accepted that NFTs aren’t yet a perfect solution to ownership, but being at least  <em>some</em>  sort of solution compared to the void of ownership traceability that existed in digital art. In a similar vein, I don’t see IPFS being an immediate perfect solution, but I think IPFS is going to do a lot in shifting NFTs from  <em>some</em>  sort of solution for digital art ownership, to a strong solution.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The pain points of NFTs]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Polygon</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/polygon/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Polygon" /><published>2022-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2022-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/polygon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/polygon/"><![CDATA[<h3 id="what-is-polygon">What is Polygon?</h3>

<p><a href="https://polygon.technology/">Polygon</a> is a Layer 2 chain for creating Ethereum compatible networks. In simple terms, it allows you to execute smart contracts on its chain that can be transferred with Ethereum, and supports the same for independent chains.</p>

<p><img src="Aspose.Words.80ac7984-f941-42df-b52f-edcf335bcbde.001.png" alt="" /></p>

<h3 id="why-im-bullish">Why I’m bullish?</h3>

<h6 id="polygon-is-scalable">Polygon is Scalable.</h6>

<p>Being a layer 2 network, Polygon solves Ethereum’s biggest issue of <a href="https://blog.coinbase.com/scaling-ethereum-crypto-for-a-billion-users-715ce15afc0b">scalability</a>. As activity on Ethereum increases, it faces high congestion. This has resulted in slower transactions and higher gas fees. As a layer 2 solution, Polygon is able to process transactions of Ethereum’s mainnet while still <a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important">holding</a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important"> </a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important">the</a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important"> </a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important">integrity</a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important"> </a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important">of</a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important"> </a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important">Ethereum</a><a href="https://www.one37pm.com/nft/tech/what-are-layer-2-solutions-and-why-are-they-important">’</a>s block chain.</p>

<p><strong>Polygon supports a multichain future.</strong></p>

<p>Polygon’s vision is to provide connectivity between different blockchains and be Ethereum’s internet of blockchains. In essence, it enables blockchains to easily bridge with Ethereum. This is promising because the future of blockchain will likely be multichain and connectivity between different blockchains will improve the user experience. What’s more, Ethereum is one of the most utilized blockchains by developers so strategically there’s a lot of opportunity in being the gateway for other blockchains to integrate with it.</p>

<p><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">Vitalik</a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099"> </a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">says</a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099"> </a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">the</a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099"> </a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">future</a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099"> </a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">is</a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099"> </a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">multichain</a><a href="https://twitter.com/VitalikButerin/status/1479501366192132099">:</a></p>

<p><img src="Aspose.Words.80ac7984-f941-42df-b52f-edcf335bcbde.002.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><img src="Aspose.Words.80ac7984-f941-42df-b52f-edcf335bcbde.003.png" alt="" /></p>

<p><strong>Polygon emphasizes value of Ethereum.</strong></p>

<p>outside of its scalability issues, Ethereum already provides significant functionality.  Unlike some layer 1 solutions to Ethereum’s problems (i.e. <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/crypto-basics/what-is-solana">Solana</a>, <a href="https://www.coinbase.com/learn/crypto-basics/what-is-cardano">Cardano</a>), Polygon builds on Ethereum instead of in place of Ethereum. It’s <a href="https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/evm/">EVM</a><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/evm/"> </a><a href="https://ethereum.org/en/developers/docs/evm/">compatible</a> which means that smart contracts deployed on the Ethereum network can be easily deployed on Polygon’s blockchain thus low switching costs. Ethereum is a largely used and trusted network with lots of strong functionalities, it makes sense to leverage this. Betting on Polygon is also betting on Ethereum.</p>

<p>To summarize – not only does polygon have improved scalability, its low switching costs and EVM compatibility reduces barriers for adoption.</p>

<p>Below is a bit more detail on Polygon’s functionality:</p>

<h2 id="how-does-polygon-work">How does Polygon work?</h2>
<p>Polygon uses an adaptation of <a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">Ethereum</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">’</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">s</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/"> </a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">Plasma</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">’</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">s</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/"> </a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/">framework</a> which allows transactions to occur off the main Ethereum network and later transferred later to the mainnet. Very simply, transactions will occur on Polygon and be bundled together as one transaction when ready to be carried over to the main Ethereum network. These individual transactions are verified on Polygon as they occur and when returned to Ethereum as a batch, are then verified by Ethereum.</p>

<p>Polygon aims to provide several options for scaling solutions. It’s primary solution is the <a href="https://finematics.com/polygon-matic-explained/#:~:text=Matic%20PoS%20Chain%20And%20Matic%20Plasma%20Chains&amp;text=Plasma%2C%20in%20essence%2C%20is%20a,for%20building%20scalable%20decentralized%20applications.&amp;text=Matic%20PoS%20Chain%20is%20a,mechanism%20with%20its%20own%20validators">PoS</a><a href="https://finematics.com/polygon-matic-explained/#:~:text=Matic%20PoS%20Chain%20And%20Matic%20Plasma%20Chains&amp;text=Plasma%2C%20in%20essence%2C%20is%20a,for%20building%20scalable%20decentralized%20applications.&amp;text=Matic%20PoS%20Chain%20is%20a,mechanism%20with%20its%20own%20validators"> </a><a href="https://finematics.com/polygon-matic-explained/#:~:text=Matic%20PoS%20Chain%20And%20Matic%20Plasma%20Chains&amp;text=Plasma%2C%20in%20essence%2C%20is%20a,for%20building%20scalable%20decentralized%20applications.&amp;text=Matic%20PoS%20Chain%20is%20a,mechanism%20with%20its%20own%20validators">chain</a> which is a permissionless side chain that uses a proof-of-stake consensus mechanism with it’s own validators, but also relies on Ethereum’s security for validator staking and check points.</p>

<h2 id="the-4-layers-of-polygon">The 4 layers of Polygon</h2>

<p>Overall, <a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9">polygon</a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9"> </a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9">can</a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9"> </a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9">be</a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9"> </a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9">broken</a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9"> </a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9">into</a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9"> 4 </a><a href="https://polygon.technology/lightpaper-polygon.pdf#page=9">layers</a> – two mandatory and two optional layers.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/pic.png" alt="Pic" /></p>

<p>The Ethereum layer, the first optional layer, allows Polygon chains to use Ethereum as it’s base layer for things like staking, dispute resolution , messaging and a few other functionalities. The security layer, the second layer, is also optional. It allows chains to add a validation as a service or use Ethereum as a security layer. The third layer is the polygon networks layer where core functions such as transaction collation, local consensus and block production occur. The last layer is the ethereum layer, which is mandatory, and interprets and executes transactions that are included in Polygon’s chains</p>

<h2 id="the-polygon-bridge">The Polygon bridge</h2>

<p>The bridge is a key part of Polygon. It is how assets are migrated between layer 2 and Ethereum. There are two implementations offered – <a href="https://docs.polygon.technology/docs/develop/ethereum-polygon/plasma/getting-started/#:~:text=A%20bridge%20is%20basically%20a,or%20Proof%20of%20Stake%20bridge.">Plasma</a><a href="https://docs.polygon.technology/docs/develop/ethereum-polygon/plasma/getting-started/#:~:text=A%20bridge%20is%20basically%20a,or%20Proof%20of%20Stake%20bridge."> </a><a href="https://docs.polygon.technology/docs/develop/ethereum-polygon/plasma/getting-started/#:~:text=A%20bridge%20is%20basically%20a,or%20Proof%20of%20Stake%20bridge.">bridge</a> and <a href="https://docs.polygon.technology/docs/develop/ethereum-polygon/pos/getting-started/">PoS</a><a href="https://docs.polygon.technology/docs/develop/ethereum-polygon/pos/getting-started/"> </a><a href="https://docs.polygon.technology/docs/develop/ethereum-polygon/pos/getting-started/">bridge</a>.</p>

<p>The Plasma bridge uses a mechanism called <a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/#fraud-proofs">Fraud</a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/#fraud-proofs"> </a><a href="https://docs.ethhub.io/ethereum-roadmap/layer-2-scaling/plasma/#fraud-proofs">proofs</a> for the main chain, Ethereum, to validate the assets being transferred from Polygon. A challenge period of 7 days is required when withdrawing funds which means it will take up to 7 days for funds to be withdrawn unto Ethereum.</p>

<p>With the PoS bridge Proof of stake based assets provides PoS security. Since this security is accepted by users and developers it does not use fraudproffs and allows for a faster exit, up to 30 minutes, with one checkpoint interval.</p>

<h2 id="in-conclusion">In conclusion</h2>

<p>Polygon solves Ethereum’s most pressing problem of scalability without directly competing against Ethereum.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[What is Polygon?]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Green_revolution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/green-revolution" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Green_revolution" /><published>2018-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/green_revolution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/green-revolution"><![CDATA[<p>Kofi Annan, suggests that a Green Revolution is necessary for Africa to improve its agriculture practices. Five ways Annan’s approach threatens traditional farming practices, and agriculture in Sub-Saharan Africa is a high cost of farming, displacement and inequality, loss of farmer independence, health and biodiversity repercussions from genetically modified seeds and negative impacts on the environment.</p>

<p><strong>High Cost of Farming</strong></p>

<p>One way which Annan’s approach presents a threat is the financial strain it puts on farmers. The Green Revolution presents a high incremental cost of farming associated with adapting its practices. Every season farmers would have to purchase seeds, chemicals and fertilizers. This would be a stark contrast for the 80% of farmers who currently use saved seeds to limit seasonal purchasing<a href="#_ftn1">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[1]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. This financial strain is further exemplified with the high cost of fertilizers. The cost of fertilizers in Sub-Saharan Africa is almost 4 times more than in European countries and increases in proportionality to distance<a href="#_ftn2">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[2]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. Consequently, farmers would experience decreased profitability from high costs and distanced landlocked countries, which are the most in need of improved accessibility, would experience the greatest burden of cost. With consideration of these financial demands and the additional inputs required for equipment and machinery, many farmers would not be able to afford adoption of these practices with many needing to take on debt.</p>

<p><strong>Labour &amp; Land displacement</strong></p>

<p>A second threat presented by Annan’s approach is labour and land displacement. The primary objective for the Green Revolution is to drastically improve production and yields through mechanisms that parallel industrial farming. This high-yield push increases demand for land and slowly shifts the agricultural landscape from nourishment based to market based<a href="#_ftn3">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[3]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. This transformation introduces a heightened threat of land displacement and land grabbing occurring, as the door opens for corporations to use large scale agriculture as a point of entry<a href="#_ftn4">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[4]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. Furthermore, as industrial practices begin to overshadow traditional practices, farming activities become consolidated and labour displacement occurs subsequently increasing rural-urban migration. There will be widened inequality as those more equipped to take on the practices of Green Revolution will outpace those who cannot afford to.</p>

<p><strong>Loss of Farmer Independence</strong></p>

<p>A third threat Annan’s approach presents is the loss of farmer independence. The implementation of a Green Revolution addresses issues of productivity and yield but does not properly mitigate the threats subsequently imposed on the independence of small farmers. Currently, small farming practices are self-sustainable in that farmers preserve their seeds, use traditional hand tools, and require low cost inputs for cultivation. In contrast, the Green Revolution calls for many corporate driven products such as genetically modified seeds, machinery, fertilizers, herbicides and pesticides. This creates a farmer dependency on corporations and transforms the farmer role from producer into consumer<a href="#_ftn5">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[5]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. Furthermore, as new industrial practices begin to be prioritized, the traditional and cultural agriculture practices amongst small farmers begins to be lost.</p>

<p><strong>Health &amp; Biodiversity Genetically Modified Seeds Create Health Implications</strong></p>

<p>A fourth threat Annan’s approach presents is health &amp; biodiversity repercussions from genetically modified seeds. These seeds are developed with chemicals and toxins that diverges from the natural produce that traditional farmers typically harvest. Although genetically modified foods have not been found to have immediate impact on health, there are postulated long term health risks that emerge from its use and cultivation. By shifting towards these seeds, the Green Revolution introduces the production of food with inconclusive effects into the African diet. In addition to health implications, Genetically Modified organisms also poses a threat to the biodiversity of its environment. As these plants continue to be cultivated and produced, they can overcome the production of preceding indigenous and native crops. Furthermore, as monohybrid crops increase in prevalence the diversity of crops planted diminishes. This reduces the variety in yield and also presents the threat of scarcity to traditional and indigenous crops.</p>

<p><strong>Impact on Environment</strong></p>

<p>A fifth threat Annan’s approach presents is that the use of chemical intensive resources, such as artificial fertilizers and chemicals, poses negative repercussions for the local environment. The continuous use of these fertilizers overtime degrades the health of the soil and leads to soil pollution<a href="#_ftn6">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[6]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. Furthermore, runoffs from chemical infused soil can often enter lakes and bodies of water also leading to depreciating water quality<a href="#_ftn7">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[7]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a>. The culminative outcome of these by-products is the deterioration of the environment and ecosystem. With a polluted ecosystem, farmers face long term issues in their agriculture conditions that may need to be addressed with further industrialized solutions. Furthermore, effects on a shared ecosystem affects even farmers that have chosen to not use fertilizers and limits their ability to continue aspects of traditional farming.</p>

<p>Conclusively, although the green revolution indicates a promise of high-yields and productivity, it also presents several threats to traditional farming practices, and agriculture in Sub-Saharan Africa.</p>

<p>&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;</p>

<hr />

<p>&lt;![endif]&gt;</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref1">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[1]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> Grant, p.114</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref2">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[2]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> World Bank</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref3">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[3]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> Grant, p.112</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref4">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[4]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> Vercillo</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref5">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[5]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> Grant, p.112</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref6">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[6]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> Kumar, R. et al.</p>

<p><a href="#_ftnref7">&lt;![if !supportFootnotes]&gt;[7]&lt;![endif]&gt;</a> NDSU</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kofi Annan, suggests that a Green Revolution is necessary for Africa to improve its agriculture practices. Five ways Annan’s approach threatens traditional farming practices, and agriculture in Sub-Saharan Africa is a high cost of farming, displacement and inequality, loss of farmer independence, health and biodiversity repercussions from genetically modified seeds and negative impacts on the environment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fintech</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/fintech" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fintech" /><published>1000-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>1000-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/fintech</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/fintech"><![CDATA[<p>With technology catapulting the accessibility of financial services in economies such as the U.S. and Canada, the FinTech industry shows promising signs of growth. Intuitively it may seem more practical for investors to focus only on developed and prospering countries but the opportunity for individuals focused on innovation and pioneering an industry could lie in developing countries like Nigeria.</p>

<p><em>Need for financial inclusivity</em></p>

<p>Only an approximate 30% of Nigerians having access to financial services, presenting a clear need for improved avenues of accessibility. With lack of financial incentive for banks to develop branches outside urban cities, mobile phones are the key to distributing these services. Though popularity of services and products vary throughout wealth levels, one of the largest commonalities in Nigeria is the mobile phone (though the most common models used are very basic) with 84% having a mobile subscription and the market contributing 7.7% to the overall GDP. A majority of those with financial access are included via digital features of their bank account indicating a pull for the accessibility and convenience of FinTech services as it aligns with the trajectory towards financial digitization. Many short comings resulting in a high financial exclusion are addressed in many business models around the world. This coupled with the prevalence of mobile phones with a positive attitude to digital services already ensures a mode of distribution leaving it up to companies to develop a business model that would leverage idea that already exists into low complexity solutions.</p>

<p><em>Potential Exists Even Amongst Poverty Line</em></p>

<p>Nigeria is one of the most populous countries in the world with 185 million people, creating a consumer base of even a percentage of its upper and middle class would provide companies with sustainable activity. Undeniably, the large presence of poverty calls into question if the remainder of Nigeria’s demographic could even translate into frequent financial activity. However, the daily transactions of those well above poverty would be supplemented by frequent money transfers attributed to Nigeria’s culture of community dependence. With a large rural to urban immigration and a motivating factor being to support emigrated rural communities, rural migrants frequently require the use of money transfers. The culture of filial responsibility further escalates the need of money transfers within the country amongst those close to the poverty line to support their family members. Additionally, from high density marketplaces to hawkers on almost every road, the exchange of money happens frequently across all income levels. In essence the lack of wealth does not imply a lack of financial service engagement. A Fintech in Nigeria could find contributions from a flourishing middle class in Nigeria culminated with the micro uses of those hovering poverty levels.</p>

<p><em>Point of Comparisons</em></p>

<p>The success of the Kenyan micro-financial service firm M-Pesa, sets a reasonable expectation as to what the implementation of fintech could look like in Nigeria. Although there is not a complete uniformity between the Kenyan and Nigerian market, the high levels of poverty and financial exclusion prevalent in both countries produces a reasonable point of initial comparison.</p>

<p>The market opportunity for financial accessibility is apparent through M-Pesa’s popularity. As of 2017, it’s transfers accounted for almost half of Kenya’s GDP . Economically, the impact was astounding. A study found that access to the service lifted 2% of Kenyan households from poverty. These comparisons could allude to an (possibly overstated) optimism in the effects of replication in a country such Nigeria. It’s important to understand that while M-pesa’s model is not guaranteed to directly be repeatable, it displays the potential for the leverage of technology to exist within poverty.</p>

<p>Nigeria’s GDP is 5 times greater than that of Kenya’s at $375.8 Billion USD and $74.9 Billion USD respectively. The success of a fintech company is supported by the presence of economic activity associated with a high GDP. If such a business witnessed enough sustainable activity in Kenya, the same can be expected in Nigeria where the GDP is larger.</p>

<p><em>Overall Potential</em></p>

<p>Companies looking to become industry pioneers could find an untapped market in Nigeria. With a lack of financial accessibility there is a need for technology to be leveraged with financial services. It is important that those entering the market cater to the capacity, while mobile phones are largely used, these entering the market must understand at what level of advancement in technology exists. The ability for a company to successfully cater to the technological capacity, as seen in Kenya’s M-Pesa, can find a way to transform extremely low wealth communities into active engagers of their financial service.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[With technology catapulting the accessibility of financial services in economies such as the U.S. and Canada, the FinTech industry shows promising signs of growth. Intuitively it may seem more practical for investors to focus only on developed and prospering countries but the opportunity for individuals focused on innovation and pioneering an industry could lie in developing countries like Nigeria.]]></summary></entry></feed>